Catherine Lynk

http://catherinelynk.com catherine.lynk@gmail.com 847-902-1751

PROFILE

Digital designer with a focus on user experience and a deep understanding of the system development lifecycle. As a client delivery team member, I have conducted research, synthesized data to drive business decisions, documented diagrams and wireframes and collaborated effectively across functional teams.

EXPERIENCE

DESIGNATION Labs

March 2015 - Present

UI / UX Design Apprentice

Anjoui - User Experience Research & Interaction Design

- Provided user experience and interaction design direction to a peer-to-peer mobile application start-up that connects home cooks with local diners
- Evaluated heuristics of the initial design, expanded wireframes through 3 rounds of usability testing and created a mid-fidelity, functional prototype
- Enabled stakeholders to interact with their concept for the first time and accelerated the timeframe from design to launch

Package Zen - User Experience Research & Content Strategy

- Addressed user experience challenges on an enterprise mobile solution that simplifies package management in offices, mailrooms and sports arenas
- Created a process map, task models and 20+ discrete wireframes based on qualitative interviews and onsite observation
- Clarified the mental model of the primary user base, allowing new features to be rolled out without disturbing the users' core workflow

ALLSTATE INSURANCE July 2014 - February 2015

Senior Consultant

- Evaluated emerging technologies, identified opportunities for enterprise innovation and presented recommendations to technology leadership
- Established internal processes based on the design thinking approach for continued use by the technology strategy team

DELOITTE CONSULTING August 2011 - July 2014

Consultant

System Transformation

- Led business requirement sessions with subject matter experts and documented user flows for the development of a global software product
- Facilitated user acceptance testing for an enterprise application, gathered feedback and worked with the development team to improve usability

Project Management

- Designed a global governance plan for the implementation an insurance claims solution across 3 international regions and 7 lines of business
- Developed a macro for analyzing and visualizing financial metrics to reduce costs and drive growth for the Deloitte Solutions Center

EDUCATION

University of Illinois 2007 - 2011 at Urbana-Champaign College of Business

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems & Information Technology

Bachelor of Science in Marketing

Bocconi University Spring 2010 Milan, Italy

University of Illinois Study Abroad

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Digital Design

Adobe Illustrator
Adobe Photoshop
Axure
InVision
Proto.io
Sketch

Front-End Development

HTML5 / CSS3 JavaScript

System Transformation

Guidewire Systems HP Quality Center MS Office Suite MS SharePoint Pega Systems

HONORS

Allstate Technology & Operations Applause Awards

Deloitte Insurance Technology Spotlight Award

Deloitte Consulting Candidate Lead for University of Illinois Recruiting